when did you start to ask yourself the question of what about palestine too freaking late
i started asking myself that question too freaking late i grew up culturally jewish
my friends my boyfriends my life was surrounded by jewish people in fact it was like kind of cool
to be jewish when i grew up i didn't even really know the concept of zionism because
zionism was just judaism right the idea that israel should be a place a safe haven for jewish
people that just was what it was the concept of birthright made total sense i didn't even
question it the fact that the government would subsidize a trip to israel so that you could see
your homeland that didn't strike me as weird at all and the jewish population is pretty small so
there's only a few degrees of separation between you and somebody who lives in israel and
that just felt like part of the package of being jewish i didn't question the fact that after the
holocaust we would need a safe haven and yes six million people dying this close in terms of the
history of the world is terrifying and yes jewish people are not the most beloved people on the planet
right traditionally we're not so yeah it made sense to me but i didn't think about how many other people
have been genocided and that they don't get their own theocratic ethnostate i didn't know that in order
to achieve that to in order to get israel to be israel that palestinians had to be forcibly removed
from their homes i didn't know that it was an illegal occupation i didn't know that israel controlled
a huge percentage of palestinians water i didn't know that it was a 75 year occupation i didn't know
that palestinians had to move through checkpoints in order to get anywhere i didn't know that 90 of
their economy is from handouts that like the world has been giving them resources because they don't
have any of their own because of said occupation i didn't know that there were thousands of palestinian
prisoners in israel that don't get a trial hundreds of whom are kids i didn't know that israel had one
of the strongest militaries in the world and provides military supplies to a lot of the rest of the world
i didn't think about the fact that putting an ally in the middle of the middle east filled with jews
as a gift from the u.s and from the british would be a super smart political tactic because none of
the rest of the world wanted us anywhere my first thought after the october 7th attack was what a
brutal horrific thing to happen to the jewish population and to the israeli civilians and i still
believe that that is true however i didn't have context and now that over 10 000 palestinians
have died now that i know that israel dropped more bombs in six days than the u.s dropped in
afghanistan in an entire year of war now that i've listened and learned for the past three weeks i wish
i had asked what about palestine sooner
you